[
    {
        "id":1,
        "question": "What is the name of the ancient Indian text that describes the science of life and virtues?",
        "choices": [
            "The Vedas",
            "The Bhagavad Gita",
            "The Ramayana",
            "The Arthashastra"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "The Arthashastra"
    },
    {
        "id":2,
        "question": "Who is considered to be the father of Indian Constitution?",
        "choices": [
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "B. R. Ambedkar",
            "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "B. R. Ambedkar"
    },
    {
        "id":3,
        "question": "What is the name of the mountain in India considered to be the center of the world and the source of all life and creation according to Hindu mythology?",
        "choices": [
            "Mount Everest",
            "Mount Kailash",
            "Mount Abu",
            "Mount Annapurna"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Mount Kailash"
    },
    {
        "id":4,
        "question": "What is the name of the ancient Indian system of medicine that is still widely practiced in India today?",
        "choices": [
            "Ayurveda",
"            Unani",
            "Siddha",
            "Allopathic"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Ayurveda"
    },
    {
        "id":5,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous rock-cut temple complex located in the southern Indian state of Tamil Nadu?",
        "choices": [
            "Ajanta Caves",
            "Ellora Caves",
            "Mahabalipuram",
            "Konark Sun Temple"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Mahabalipuram"
    },
    {
        "id":6,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous classical dance form originating from the Indian state of Tamil Nadu?",
        "choices": [
            "Bharatanatyam",
            "Kathakali",
            "Odissi",
            "Manipuri"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Bharatanatyam"
    },
    {
        "id":7,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Hindu festival that celebrates the victory of good over evil and the arrival of spring?",
        "choices": [
            "Diwali",
            "Holi",
            "Navaratri",
            "Raksha Bandhan"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Holi"
    },
    {
        "id":8,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian epic poem that narrates the life of Lord Rama and his journey to rescue his wife Sita from the demon king Ravana?",
        "choices": [
            "Mahabharata",
            "Ramayana",
            "Puranas",
            "Upanishads"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Ramayana"
    },
    {
        "id":9,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian mathematician and astronomer known for his work on the approximation of pi and the concept of zero?",
        "choices": [
            "Aryabhata",
            "Brahmagupta",
            "Varahamihira",
            "Bhaskara"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Aryabhata"
    },
    {
        "id":10,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian king who is said to have ruled the Mauryan Empire from 269 BC to 232 BC?",
        "choices": [
"            Asoka",
            "Chandragupta",
            "Bindusara",
            "Dharmashoka"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Asoka"
    },
    {
        "id":11,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian philosopher and teacher who was the founder of Buddhism and is known as the Buddha?",
        "choices": [
            "Mahavira",
            "Gautama Buddha",
            "Parshvanatha",
            "Neminatha"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Gautama Buddha"
    },
    {
        "id":12,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian queen who was the wife of King Ashoka and is known for promoting Buddhism?",
        "choices": [
            "Dharmashoka",
            "Padmavati",
            "Tishyaraksha",
            "Dharma"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Dharma"
    },
    {
        "id":13,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian mathematician and astronomer who is known for his work on the calculation of the value of pi and the area of a circle?",
        "choices": [
            "Brahmagupta",
            "Aryabhata",
            "Varahamihira",
            "Bhaskara"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Bhaskara"
    },
    {
        "id":14,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian epic poem that tells the story of the Kuru kingdom and the struggle between the Pandavas and the Kauravas for the throne?",
        "choices": [
            "Ramayana",
            "Mahabharata",
            "Puranas",
            "Upanishads"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Mahabharata"
    },
    {
        "id":15,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian independence leader who is known as the 'Iron Man of India'?",
        "choices": [
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "B. R. Ambedkar"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel"
    },
    {
        "id":16,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian independence leader who is known for his nonviolent resistance and is referred to as the 'Mahatm'?",
        "choices": [
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "B. R. Ambedkar"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Mahatma Gandhi"
    },
    {
        "id":17,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian independence leader who was the first Prime Minister of India after independence from British rule?",
        "choices": [
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "B. R. Ambedkar"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Jawaharlal Nehru"
    },
    {
        "id":18,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian independence leader who was a social reformer and is known for his work on the caste system and the rights of the Dalits?",
        "choices": [
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "B. R. Ambedkar"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "B. R. Ambedkar"
    },
    {
        "id":19,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian monument that was built in the memory of Queen Mumtaz Mahal, the wife of the Mughal Emperor Shah Jahan?",
        "choices": [
            "Taj Mahal",
            "Qutub Minar",
            "Red Fort",
            "Humayuns Tomb"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Taj Mahal"
    },
    {
        "id":20,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian monument that was built by the Mughal Emperor Shah Jahan as a symbol of his love for his wife Mumtaz Mahal?",
        "choices": [
            "Taj Mahal",
            "Qutub Minar",
            "Red Fort",
            "Humayun s Tomb"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Taj Mahal"
    },
    {
        "id":21,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian monument that was built as a victory tower by Qutb-ud-din Aibak after the defeat of the Delhi s last Hindu kingdom?",
        "choices": [
            "Taj Mahal",
            "Qutub Minar",
            "Red Fort",
            "Humayun s Tomb"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Qutub Minar"
    },
    {
        "id":22,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian monument that was built by the Mughal Emperor Shah Jahan in Delhi as his residence and palace?",
        "choices": [
            "Taj Mahal",
            "Qutub Minar",
            "Red Fort",
            "Humayun s Tomb"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Red Fort"
    },
    {
        "id":23,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian monument that was built by the Mughal Emperor Humayun as his final resting place?",
        "choices": [
            "Taj Mahal",
            "Qutub Minar",
            "Red Fort",
            "Humayun s Tomb"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Humayun s Tomb"
    },
    {
        "id":24,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian epic that tells the story of the prince Rama and his rescue of his wife Sita from the demon king Ravana?",
        "choices": [
            "Mahabharata",
            "Ramayana",
            "Bhagavad Gita",
            "Puranas"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Ramayana"
    },
    {
        "id":25,
        "question": "What is the name of the famous Indian epic that tells the story of a great war between the Pandavas and the Kauravas for the kingdom of Hastinapura?",
        "choices": [
            "Mahabharata",
            "Ramayana",
            "Bhagavad Gita",
            "Puranas"
        ],
        "type": "MCQs",
        "correctAnswer": "Mahabharata"
    }
]
